This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
天気予報
本日未明から明日にかけての 鹿児島県 種子島 屋久島地方は
Weather forecast.
For the area of Tanegashima and Yakushima in Kagoshima prefecture
曇り後 雨でしょう
from dawn today until tomorrow.
Only clouds and rain are predicted.
今日は 嵐になりそうですね
Today will be stormy...
すれ違う　言葉の裏に
閉ざされた　心の鍵
Behind the words passing by
The key of my closed heart is hidden
君という　フラグ解除が
笑顔救えるのなら
If setting your flag
Could save your smile
夏の風いざなう　白昼のスコール
The late summer breeze
波長シンクロ
Turns into a midday squall
ロマンチックみたいに　気の利いた言葉も
As we sync our wavelengths
I'm such a bad romantic
見つからないけど　青空を目指すから
Can't even find
Any words with an edge
Still I aim for the blue sky
僕たちは　一つになれる
戸惑いの涙も　夢も
We can become one
As our dreams and confused tears
真実に　引き寄せられるもの
Draw us ever closer to the truth
それは愛しすぎる
魔法のキーワード
That becomes our beloved
本字幕由諸神字幕組出品,僅供學習交流之用 更多中日雙語字幕，請登錄 www.kamigami.org
---諸神字幕組---
台本：卷
翻译:臭屁匠 苜汐瞳
校对: mam
后期:Ressul zzz
Magical keyword
The hell's going on here?
どうなってるんだか
Not to mention...
しかも…
I'm Tennouji Nae. Nice to meet you!
Love people, revere heaven
This is the space center, right?
宇宙センターだよね… ここ
L-Lemme tell you all that happened to me as it happened!
あ… ありのまま 今 起こったことを話すぜ
I went to the nearby store for Pocchi, and the next thing I knew I was here at J-JAXA.
私は 近所のコンビニにポッチィを買いに出たと思ったら
ジャ… ＪＡＸＡにいた
I guess I don't make much sense, but I don't really know myself what happened.
な… 何を言っているか分からねえと思うが
私も 何を されたのか分からなかった
They just put you in a car and kidnapped you, didn't they?
こなちゃんも車に押し込まれて拉致されたんでしょ
That pretty much covers it.
だ… だいたい合ってる
Guys, I remember a case like this from before.
みんな うち 今回みたいなケース前に見たことあるんだ
That's the Gendo pose, isn't it?
それ ゲンドウポーズですか
You recognize it?
分かるか
You remember a case like this?
見たことあるって？
It happens all the time in robot anime!
ロボットアニメでよくあるパターンだよ
つまり うちらは正義のロボットを動かすチームに選ばれたってことで
It means they've chosen us as the team to operate the robot of justice!
That's hilariously lame.
ホントに くだらないですね
や… やあ
H-Hey.
Dad!
お父さん これ お父さんの差し金？
You're behind this?! What's going on?!
どういうこと
Allow me to explain.
私から説明します
I'm Tennouji Nae from the JAXA Innovative Technology Research Center.
ＪＡＸＡ研究開発本部未踏技術開発センターの 天王寺綯です
Nice to meet you!
よろしく
The reason we're all here today...
今日 集まっていただいた理由は…
Make a giant robot        together with JAXA!
Make a giant robot         together with JAXA!
is this!
これです
Make a giant robot together with JAXA!
ＪＡＸＡと一緒に 巨大ロボットを造ろう
Make a giant robot        together with JAXA!
With JAXA? A giant robot?
ＪＡＸＡと巨大ロボットを
はい 正しくは革新ロボティクス技術研究支援事業っていうんですけど
Yes.
To be exact, it's the Innovative Technology Research Center's Robotics Support Project.
The point is, we'd like to support people developing giant robots.
まあ 要するに巨大ロボットを研究開発している人たちに
援助をしたいなぁという話です
The goal is to make it to the Tokyo Expo next year.
目標は 来年の東京万博への出展
万博
The Expo?!
But sadly, the project is badly financed.
とはいえ 予算はと～っても少ないです
A bird could make more money by chirping.
すずめの涙です 支援対象は１つが限界
We were wondering who should we support, and then we saw the Robo-One.
で どこにしようかと考えていたときに
ＲＯＢＯ－ＯＮＥを見ました
You stood your ground against the legendary Mister Pleiades!
あの英雄ミスター?プレアデスと互角の戦いを繰り広げていましたね
But Mister Pleiades is right he—
ミスター?プレアデスなら ここに…
P-Please don't say unnecessary things!
余計にゃこと言わないでくだちゃい
We read the interview that you gave to the Kaiuri paper as well.
買読新聞の 瀬乃宮さんのインタビューも読ませてもらいました
You said that your dream is to create a 10 meter tall giant robot.
全高１０ｍ以上ある巨大ロボットを造るのが夢だって言ってましたよね
That's when we realized you're the one we were looking for!
それで これだ と
But I'm relieved.
でも よかった
Many researchers and companies must be targeting you already.
皆さんのことは すでにいろんな研究機関や企業が狙っているはずですから
That's why we were in a bit of a rush to invite you here.
Make a giant robot        together with JAXA!
それで お呼びするのに手荒なまねをしてしまったというわけです
I sincerely apologize!
本当に すみませんでした
いろんな研究機関や企業
Many researchers and companies?!
That was obviously flattery.
単なるお世辞でしょ
So how would you support us?
で 具体的にはどう支援してもらえるんですか
We'll provide research funding,
開発費を提供します
and our scientists will provide you with advice too.
さらに うちの技術者からアドバイスを受けることも可能です
That sounds way too good to be true.
どう考えてもいい話過ぎるんだけど
Well, I can only ask you to believe me...
信じてくださいって言うしかないですね
But if the finished robot is well received,
でも 完成したロボットの評価が高ければ
we might rely on you to build other robots in the future!
将来 巨大ロボの製作を皆さんに依頼するかもしれませんよ
A JAXA robot of justice that will defeat the armies of evil in a flash!
悪の軍団をばったばったとなぎ倒していく正義のＪＡＸＡロボ
How about it?
どうですか
That sounds like a weapon to me...
それじゃ 兵器じゃないか
そんなコンセプトは認められないよ
I can never agree to such a concept.
I'm just joking, sir!
いや 冗談です
No!
いい
I love that way of thinking!
そういう考え方 大好きです
Oh man, she bit on it.
食い付いちゃった
Really? Thanks!
本当？ ありがとう
We wanted to go to the Expo anyway,
万博には出るつもりでしたし
so we're building a giant robot with you!
ＪＡＸＡと一緒に巨大ロボ… 造ります
よかった
That's great!
Well then, can we see the giant robot you're building?
では 皆さんが造っている巨大ロボット見せてもらっちゃおうかな
But of course!
もちろんです
I can't believe you rejected JAXA's help...
信じられません ＪＡＸＡの支援を断るなんて
They'd have us abandon No. 1 and build a new one from scratch.
だって １号機を凍結して新しい巨大ロボを造れだなんて
Plans? You drew them?
設計図 お姉ちゃんが描いたの
You're building Gunvarrel?
お姉ちゃんがガンヴァレル造るの
It's the Gunvarrel Production Test No. 1, the GunPro-1!
ガンヴァレル試作１号機 ガンつく１よ
I want to finish the GunPro-1.
うちが完成させたいのはガンつく１なんだ
I can't even imagine working on another robot.
それ以外のロボットを造るなんて考えられないよ
Akiho...
あき穂ちゃん
Yashio, what do you think?
八汐先輩 先輩はどう思いますか
別に どっちみち手伝う気ないし
Whatever. I wasn't helping either way.
You're like that again?!
もう またそういうこと言う
手伝ってほしかったら 俺と勝負…
If you want me to help, then beat me in—
Damn you!
こんにゃろ
Total, utter nonsense.
まったく ナンセンスだ
Hidden Number
Aki
Mom
Home
Aki
Tennouji, you should leave for today.
天王寺君 今日はもう帰った方がよさそうだよ
はい それより言わなくてよかったんですか
Yessir.
But are you sure we shouldn't tell her this support project was your idea?
あき穂ちゃんに 今回の件は所長が言い出しっぺだって
I got way too nervous when it came to that.
面と向かうと照れてしまってね
I didn't expect my daughter to refuse though.
しかし まさか娘が拒否するとは思わなかったよ
I'm really sorry.
本当に申し訳ない
It's nothing. But isn't it nice?
いえいえ
でも いいですよね 仲間で集まって何か造ったり研究したり
She gathered a team to build and research.
I really like that kind of person!
そういう人たち好きなんですよね
I'll try to approach her a little more!
もう少し アプローチしてみます
Brother, the typhoon's here!
お兄ちゃん 台風が来てますよ
I know.
知ってるよ
Hidden number
Incoming call
Accept
Reject
Hidden number
Incoming call
Accept
Reject
Hidden number
Incoming call
Accept
Reject
Say, Airi, do you know anything about that Kagome-Kagome phone call?
愛理ちゃんさ 『かごめかごめ』の電話について何か覚えある？
『かごめかごめ』？ 歌ですよね
Kagome-Kagome? You mean the song, right?
歌じゃなくて 電話の着信音
Not the song itself. It was used as a ringtone.
Would Sister Centipede know?
ゲジ姉なら知ってるかな
Access confirmed.
アクセス確認しました ゲジ姉モードに移行します
Switching to Sister Centipede mode.
Do you know about the Kagome-Kagome ringtone?
『かごめかごめ』の電話について何か知ってる？
It occurred all over Japan.
日本全国で発生したようです
Is there a second and third Kimijima Report as well?
君島レポートって ナンバー２とか３はあるの
Yes. Up to number 7.
はい ナンバー７まで存在します
That's quite a lot.
結構あるな
Do you know where they are?
どこにあるかは分かってるの
Airi and Sister Centipede have no knowledge whatsoever
愛理 および ゲジ姉は
君島レポートが隠蔽されている全ての場所については把握していません
regarding all locations of the hidden Kimijima reports.
Does that mean you know some locations?
ってことは 一部なら把握してる？
Yes.
はい 君島レポートナンバー２はこの宇宙ヶ丘公園近辺にあります
The second Kimijima report is located here, in the vicinity of Space Hill Park.
Huh? So close by?
何だ すぐ近くじゃない
At present, the Kimijima report's A.R. marker does not appear in Iru-O.
現在の状況では 『居ル夫。』に
君島レポートのＡＲマーカーは表示されません
Why?
どうして
Each Kimijima report has a condition for visibility, a certain flag.
各君島レポートには可視化するための解除条件フラグが存在します
A flag?
フラグ
So the "hiddenhand" won't work here?
ヒドゥンハンドは通用しないってわけ
って ちょっと待って 君島コウが死んだのっていつだっけ
Wait a moment now. When did Kimijima Kou die again?
2010.
２０１０年です
The Iru-O existed back then?
その時点で「居ル夫。」ってあったの
The alpha version was under development.
α版が開発されていました
And what's this flag for visibility?
それで 可視化するためのフラグって？
Downloading the flag for report number two.
レポートナンバー２のフラグをダウンロードします
Download completed without any problems.
ダウンロードは正常に完了しまし
First: Find Kimijima report no. 1 and contact Airi at least once.
１ 君島レポート１を発見し 愛理と一度でもコンタクトを取る
Second: Under the radar dome at the South-Tanegashi Folk Museum,
２ 南種子町 旧郷土館レーダードーム下部にある緑色のスイッチを押し
press the green button once, and after an hour, press it again.
１時間後に もう一度押す
Third: Complete the Space Hill Park's go-kart course's time attack under 30 seconds,
３ 宇宙ヶ丘公園のゴーカートコースタイムアタックで３０秒を切り
and sync the time record with the Iru-O geo-tag as proof.
『居ル夫。』ジオタグにてタイムを申告 署名する」
Fourth: Get SSS rating in the fighter game "Golden Wolf Fighter 4,"
４ 格闘ゲームアプリ『黄金狼ＦＩＧＨＴＥＲⅣ』
アーケードモードで ＳＳＳの成績を出し
オンラインリーダーボードに記録をアップロードする
and record the result on the online leaderboard.
何だ こりゃ
Why does it have to be so troublesome?
何で こんな面倒なことを？
Only Master knows that.
マスターにしか分かりません
This is pretty much just playing games...
これじゃ ゲームじゃん レーダードームって
And that radar dome...
Whoa, it's really there.
うわっ ホントにあったよ
What?!
何だ
I totally should've just gone home.
やっぱり 帰ればよかった
This brings back memories.
懐かしい アプリ版あったんだ
I didn't know there was an app version of it too.
It was popular almost ten years ago.
はやったのって １０年くらい前だよな
よくミサ姉にぼこぼこにされたっけ
Misa always beat me to a pulp in it.
It's a good enough way to spend that one hour.
１時間… 暇をつぶすにはちょうどいいか
Outgoing message
Today JAXA people came
Sis
Today JAXA people came and told us they'd help us build a robot.
But they had a condition...
They want us to abandon the GunPro-1 and build a new robot.
The obvious choice would've been to accept without any questions, but I refused.
It's our dream to complete the GunPro-1 after all!
Am I being selfish here? What do you think?
Sorry for disturbing when you're so busy.
Good luck with your work.
Today JAXA people came and told us they'd help us build a robot.
But they had a condition...
They want us to abandon the GunPro-1 and build a new robot.
The obvious choice would've been to accept without any questions, but I refused.
It's our dream to complete the GunPro-1 after all!
Am I being selfish here? What do you think?
Sorry for disturbing when you're so busy.
Good luck with your work.
Outgoing message
Today JAXA people came
Sis
Today JAXA people came and told us they'd help us build a robot.
But they had a condition...
They want us to abandon the GunPro-1 and build a new robot.
The obvious choice would've been to accept without any questions, but I refused.
It's our dream to complete the GunPro-1 after all!
Am I being selfish here? What do you think?
Sorry for disturbing when you're so busy.
Good luck with your work.
Sending
送信
Today JAXA people came and told us they'd help us build a robot.
But they had a condition...
They want us to abandon the GunPro-1 and build a new robot.
The obvious choice would've been to accept without any questions, but I refused.
It's our dream to complete the GunPro-1 after all!
Am I being selfish here? What do you think?
Sorry for disturbing when you're so busy.
Good luck with your work.
Send!
Today JAXA people came and told us they'd help us build a robot.
But they had a condition...
They want us to abandon the GunPro-1 and build a new robot.
The obvious choice would've been to accept without any questions, but I refused.
It's our dream to complete the GunPro-1 after all!
Am I being selfish here? What do you think?
Sorry for disturbing when you're so busy.
Good luck with your work.
Today JAXA people came and told us they'd help us build a robot.
But they had a condition...
They want us to abandon the GunPro-1 and build a new robot.
The obvious choice would've been to accept without any questions, but I refused.
It's our dream to complete the GunPro-1 after all!
Am I being selfish here? What do you think?
Sorry for disturbing when you're so busy.
Good luck with your work.
Sending
よっしゃ フラグ達成
Hell yeah! Flag set!
It's been a while, so it took quite some time.
久しぶりだったから 結構てこずっちゃったなぁ
Oh, damn.
しまった
Airi warned you about the typhoon beforehand.
台風が来ていると 愛理は事前に警告したはずです
Thanks for reminding me.
そうだったね
何だ
What?!
Isn't that...
これって…
a plate from the radar dome?!
レーダードームのプレートだ
Was the plate blown off by the wind?
プレートが風で飛ばされてきたのですか
Is it gonna be alright?
これって 大丈夫なのか
In that case the antenna might have suffered damage as well, not just the dome.
その場合 ドームだけでなく アンテナ本体に破損の恐れがあります
When you opened the dome earlier, you made the antenna vulnerable to wind damage.
先ほど 八汐さんがドームを開放したことで
風雨に対し無防備になっていると思われます
So now it's my fault?
俺のせいかよ
What's gonna happen if the antenna breaks?
で あのドームがぶっ壊れたら フラグはどうなる？
There is a possibility that the flag cannot be set.
達成できなくなる可能性があります
Sister Centipede, are you telling me to protect the antenna?
ゲジ姉 まさか俺にあのアンテナを守れとでも言いたいわけ？
ゲジ姉を終了します
Ending Sister Centipede mode.
I hope the antenna will be okay...
鉄塔 大丈夫でしょうか
Is that the first thing you've got to say on your return?
開口一番 それかよ
If the antenna breaks, I'll have one less job.
アンテナが壊れたら 愛理のお仕事１つ減っちゃいますね
What job?
仕事？
Master gave me this task.
マスターから もらったお仕事です
Every day I must check if the beep-beep-boop sound broadcasts properly.
１日１回 ピピーブーっていう音がちゃんと出てるのを聞くこと
I must also check if there are any changes.
その後 何か変わったことがないか見ること
That's your job?
それが仕事？
Yeah, I've been doing it for ten years now!
はい もう１０年くらい続けています
But if I can't do that anymore, I'll have one less thing to do.
でも それがなくなっちゃうと 愛理のやること１つ減っちゃいますね
I shouldn't have asked.
聞くんじゃなかった
Phew, that scared me!
びっくりした
Aki, do you know where Kai is?
アキちゃん カイ君どこ行ったか知らない？
What?
He's still not at home!
まだ 帰ってないんですって
Why do I have to do this?!
何で俺がこんなこと
She's just an AI!
相手はＡＩだぞ
Whatever happens to some AI's job, that has nothing to do with m—
ＡＩの仕事とやらがどうなろうと俺には関係…
Damn!
くっそ
Brother, thanks a lot! Now I can continue my job!
お兄ちゃん ありがとうございます
これで 愛理のお仕事続けられます
I wish I could carry you...
愛理が お兄ちゃんのこと運べればいいんですけど
そっちは… 平和そう… だね
Your side looks so peaceful.
I'm not conscious of the weather.
愛理には天候の変化 分かりません
I can only see the data uploaded to Iru-O.
愛理に見えているのは「居ル夫。」にアップロードされたデータです
So I can't understand the pain you're feeling now.
だから愛理には 今のお兄ちゃんの苦しみが理解できません
But Brother, don't give up yet! Just a little more and—
でも お兄ちゃん 頑張って もう少しで…
Kai! Kai! Kai!
カイ カイ
Kai!
Aki...
アキ… ちゃん
You moron! What are you doing?!
バカ 何やってるのよ
Why are you here?
何で ここに？
I thought you might be here, so I came looking for you.
もしかしたら 公園にいるかなって思って捜しに来たら
愛理っていう子がうちの「居ル夫。」に出てきたの
Then this girl called Airi showed up in my Iru-O.
それで ここにカイがいるから助けてって教えてくれて
She told me that you're here and that I should save you.
How do you wanna get off here?
で… どうやって下りるつもり？
だ… 大丈夫 下にお父さんたちいるし
It'll be fine. Dad and a few others came with me.
I owe you my life, Aki.
アキちゃんは 俺の命の恩人だな
That reminds me of the SS Anemone.
あねもね号のときのこと思い出すね
Yesterday, I was taken to the hospital after that.
昨日は あれから病院へ行った
This afternoon I visited the people I caused trouble for to apologize
そして 今日は午後から迷惑を掛けたご近所さんたちに謝罪に回り
and explained Airi to Aki.
アキちゃんには愛理のことを説明した
Then the last flag...
そして 最後のフラグ ゴーカートコースは封鎖されていたが
The go-kart course was closed,
but when I uploaded a fake time to the geo-tag,
そこにあったジオタグに架空のタイムを申告したら あっさり達成
I managed to set the flag.
I found the second Kimijima report.
君島レポートナンバー２を手に入れた
"The organization known as The Committee of 300,
ＮＡＳＡに圧力を加えたのは
"a group that controls the world from the shadows,
３００人委員会と呼ばれる世界を陰から動かしている存在である
"gained more and more power.
"They are following their 'Human Domestication Project,'
人類牧場化計画という全人類を１０億人まで減らし
"through which they intend to decrease human population to one billion,
プロパガンダを用いて世界統一政府を作ることを目的としている
"and create a unified world government using propaganda.
"Watch out for Kagome-Kagome.
『かごめかごめ』には注意を払え
それは 彼らにとってシンボルのような歌であり
"That song holds a symbolic meaning to them,
実験が行われる所には確実に その歌の存在が見え隠れするはずだ
"and wherever they conduct an experiment, you will be sure to encounter it."
The blinding light of childhood memories
幼い思い出　眩しい波光に
Turns the scenery of my dream
夢に見た景色は
Into monochrome as it lies forgotten
置き忘れたまま
モノクロになって
And vanishes from my eyes
瞳から消える
But you've always been
だけどいつでも君は
Looking straight at the future
まっすぐ明日を見つめた
And you paid the price in tears
どれくらいの涙と引き換えに
So we turn our hesitation
だから僕らの迷いも
Into strength by the power
強さに変えてくれる
Of our connected hearts
繋がった心が解き放つ
Feel it! These overflowing emotions
不意に溢れ出す思い
For that someone in the sunset
同じに誰かのために
I'll use what little courage I have
この小さな勇気で
And overcome the rage of the wind
風が吹き荒れても
Because I want to protect you
君を守りたくて
Tune in next week too!
I'm Tennouji Nae. Nice to meet you!
Now I'm on fire!